Simon Krafft

Front-End Engineer

Personal Info

Address

Boise, ID

Phone

914-620-7262

E-mail

krafftsimon@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/krafftsimon/

GitHub

https://github.com/krafftsimon

Personal Website

http://www.krafftsimon.com

Technologies

HTML / CSS

React / Redux

Node.js / Express.js

Google Cloud | AWS

Git

Webpack

Programming Languages

Javascript

C++

Java

Python

I am an innovative Front-End Engineer offering experience with various programming languages and technologies. I have significant exposure to modern Front-End frameworks like Angular and React. I am eager and very capable of learning new technologies. I consistently take initiative when given creative license, and I am comfortable collaborating with clients and internal engineering/product/design teams to gather requirements.

Experience

2018-08 -

present

Full-Stack Developer

Bodybuilding.com

- Translated Wire frames to code with pixel perfect accuracy while maintaining an excellent page speed score.
- Worked on finding, and customizing a new CMS that would fulfill our needs when making highly dynamic web pages.
- Improved header-bidding, and implemented server-side bidding to greatly increase ad impressions and ad revenue.
- Maintained and improved various systems, and codebases using a large range of different programming languages and technologies.

2018-02 -

Front-End Engineer

present AlgoExpert

- Drastically improved the website's performance, and brought the initial page load down by several seconds using techniques such as lazy-loading, and code-splitting.
- Implemented a fully functional, feature-rich online coding workspace.
- Contributed to the responsiveness of the website, allowing it to become fully
 usable on mobile devices and thereby increasing ad campaign conversion rates
 and the number of daily visits to the website.
- Designed and implemented a service to continually check the health of the website, tracking errors and average request duration.
- Created a User Interface that communicates with the new service's API to organize and display various information.

Education

2012-09 -

McGill University, Bachelor of Engineering - Computer

Projects

Mean Stack Web App

Single-page web application with Angular 4, using Express.js (Node.js) on the server and MongoDB as the DBMS. Includes Authn/Authz functionality and allows the user to generate a workout routine and track/save their progress.

Online Multiplayer Game

Pong mini-game using socket.io; implemented an authoritative server architecture to prevent cheating; analyzed network patterns and profiled the client-server interactions to reduce latency and improve gameplay experience